Guide to the Edward Lee Plumb Papers, 1856-1912
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE 1874, May - June (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 25. 1874, June 19.E.L. Plumb to Alvin S. Southworth., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1874, June 20.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1874, June 23.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1874, June 24.H. Clarke to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1874, June 24.H. Clarke to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 30. 1874, June 26.Grace S. Bristed to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1874, June 26.E.L. Plumb to Carl Schurz., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1874, June 27.E.L. Plumb to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1874, June 27.Alvin S. Southworth to E.L. Plumb to, A.L.S., copy.
  - 34. 1874, June 27.Extract of confidential ltr. Unknown to unknown.
  - 35. 1874, June 29.[Chambrun] to unknown., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1874, June 30.E.L. Plumb to Wm. H. Swift., A.L.S.
  - 37. [1874, June?].[Sevellen] A. Brown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1874, July - September (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1. 1874, July 1.E.L. Plumb to Wm. H. Swift., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1874, July 2.Hyde Clarke to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 3. 1874, July 8.E.L. Plumb to W.W. Curtis., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1874, July 9.E.L. Plumb to David A. Wells., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1874, July 10.Estanislao Cañedo to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 6. 1874, July 10.E.L. Plumb to George F. Church., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1874, July 11.E.L. Plumb to Wm. H. Swift., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1874, July 12.Blas Balcarcel to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 9. 1874, July 12.Estanislao Cañedo to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 10. 1874, July 12.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb. Another Mexican RR Co., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1874, July 16.E.L. Plumb to Sevellon A. Brown., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1874, July 22.P.R. Pyne to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1874, [July 22].W. H. Swift to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1874, July 30.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1874, July 31.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1874, July 31.E.L. Plumb to John L. Geiger. Arrival in England., Tel.
  - 17. 1874, Aug. 1.[A. Santacilia?] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 18. 1874, Aug. 2.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., Tel.
  - 19. 1874, Aug. 4.Alex L. Curran to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1874, Aug. 6.Alex L. Curran to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1874, Aug. 7.N. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1874, Aug. 22.Blas Balcarcel to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 23. 1874, Aug. 22.[William Blackman] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1874, Aug. 28.[G. de Corvantes] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 25. 1874, Aug.].Charles D. Poston to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. & 27. 1874, Sep. 2.E.L. Plumb to Caleb Cushing., 2 A.L.S.
  - 28. 1874, Sep. 7.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1874, Sep. 7.[John Hill] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1874, Sep. 8.J.H. [Fulsten?] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1874, Sep. 11.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1874, Sep. 13.E.L. Plumb to John L. Geiger., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1874, Sep. 16.James M. Swank to E.L. Plumb. Iron ore, iron & steel production., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1874, Sep. 23.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1874, Sep. 25.E.L. Plumb to J. Lowthian Bell., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1874, Sep. 26.Walton W. Evans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1874, Sep. 26.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 38. 1874, Sep. 28.E.L. Plumb to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1874, [Sep.?].E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1874, Dec. 28.Printed invitation in Sp. to attend a banquet of the Association del Ano Nuevo.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1874, October - December (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1. 1874, Oct. 1.E.L. Plumb to Wm. Henry Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1874, Oct. 4.M.I. Madrid to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 3. 1874, Oct. 5.E.L. Plumb to William Bond., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1874, Oct. 5.E.L. Plumb to J.S. Kennedy., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1874, Oct. 5.E.L. Plumb to Henry G. Marquand., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1874, Oct. 7.H.G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1874, Oct. 8.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1874, Oct. 8.William Bond to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 9. 1874, Oct. 9.S.D. [Doremans] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. & 11. 1874, Oct. 9.John S. Kennedy to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. & copy.
  - 12. 1874, Oct. 15.E.L. Plumb to Wm. Walter Phelps., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1874, Oct. 17.E.L. Plumb to John S. Kennedy., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1874, Oct. 20.E.L. Plumb to Henry G. Marquand., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1874, Oct. 26.John S. Barnes to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1874, Oct. 26.E.L. Plumb to W. Thos. Morrison., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1874, Oct. 26.E.L. Plumb to James M. Swank., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1874, Oct. 28.Albert Rierstadt to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1874, Oct. 30.William Newbold to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1874, Oct. 31.E.L. Plumb to Baring Bros. & Co., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1874, Oct. 31.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1874, Oct. 31.E.L. Plumb to Nathaniel Davidson., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1874, Nov. 1.John L. Geiger to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1874, Nov. 5.George Earl Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1874, Nov. 5.H.G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1874, Nov. 14.[B. S. de Pothonier] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1874, Nov. 15.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1874, Nov. 18.W. Thos. Morrison to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1874, Dec. 1.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1874, Dec. 5.E.L. Plumb to J.S. Kennedy., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1874, Dec. 9.El Vice-presidente y miembres de la Sociedad de Beneficencia de Esta Capital., Ptd. form ltr. in Sp.
  - 32. 1874, Dec. 12.Contrato celebrado entre el C. Ministro de Fomento, en representacion del Ejecutive de la Union y el representante de la Campania del Ferrocarril Internacional de Texas. Blas Balcarcel & E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
  - 33. 1874, Dec. 15.E.L. Plumb to Robert Benson & Co., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1874, Dec. 15.E.L. Plumb to J.S. Kennedy., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1874, Dec. 17.Thos. Allen to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1874, Dec. 17.Mr. & Mrs. Kauffman., A.N.S.
  - 37. 1874, Dec. 19.R.S. Newbold to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 38. 1874, Dec. 26.E.L. Plumb to J.S. Kennedy., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1874, Dec. 28.Juan Collado to [E.L. Plumb]., Ptd. L.S. in Sp.
  - 40. 1874, Dec. 29.E.L. Plumb to R.S. Hayes, A.L.S.
  - 41. 1874, Dec. 31.E.L. Plumb to Grace S. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1874, Dec. 31 - June 21, 1875.Extract, Central Railroad Concession.
  - 43. 1874, Dec. 31.Importation of sugar, molasses & coffee., Clips.
  - 44. 1874, Dec.Jose M. Iglesias & Manuel Peredo., Ptd. L.
  - 45. [1974?].Mr. & Mrs. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 46. [1974?].R. Van [Linnburg] to [E.L. Plumb.], A.N.S.
  - 47. - 49. [1874?].Lists of statistics-elevation, population & area.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1875, January - April (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1. 1875, Jan. 1.Tho. Allen to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1875, Jan. 1.Estanislao Caneda to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1875, Jan. 2.[H. Santacilia] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 4. 1875, Jan. 5.Invitation to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. L. in Sp.
  - 5. 1875, Jan. 7.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
  - 6. 1875, Jan. 19.Robt. Benson & Co. to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 7. 1875, Feb. 7.Josephine Fentor to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1875, Feb. 9.George Earl Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1875, Feb. 9.Hyde Clarke to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1875, Feb. 15.A. Nuñez Ortega to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1875, Feb. 16.E.L. Plumb to Thos. Allen., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1875, Feb. 22.E.L. Plumb to T.R. McFerson., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1875, Feb. 28.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1875, Mar. 2.John W. Foster to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1875, Mar. 5.W.H. Hurlbert to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1875, Mar. 8.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1875, Mar. 9.E.L. Plumb to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1875, Mar. 11.Mary H. [Doremans] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1875, Mar. 12.E.L. Plumb to unknown in London., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1875, Mar. 19.Henry G. Marquand to E.L. Plumb. Notarized official letter., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1875, Mar. 24.Geo. J. Forrest to E.L. Plumb. Notarized., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1875, Mar. 24.T.M.R. Talcott to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1875, Mar. 25.Sam Sloan to E.L. Plumb. Notarized., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1875, Mar. 27.Robt. Benson & Co. to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1875, Apr. 7.F.W. Peirce to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1875, Apr. 15.E.L. Plumb to Thomas Allen., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1875, Apr. 15.Luis G. Segura to E.L. Plumb., Ptd. L.S. in Sp.
  - 28. 1875, Apr. 16.E.L. Plumb to Wm. Walter Phelps., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1875, Apr. 17.Manuel Madrid to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 30. 1875, Apr. 17.Wm. Walter Phelps to E.L. Plumb., Tel. in Sp.
  - 31. 1875, Apr. 17.E.L. Plumb to R.S. Hayes., A.N.S.
  - 32. 1875, Apr. 22.Eliza Enzenberg to [E.L. Plumb?]., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1875, Apr. 24.J.M. Mata to E.L. Plumb., A.M.S. in Sp.
  - 34. 1875, Apr. 24.Jose M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., D.S. in Sp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1875, May - August (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1. May 1.E.L.P. to Goldlove S. Orth., A.L.S.
  - 2. May 2.Matias Romero to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. May 8.Wm. Walter Phelps to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. May 9.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. May 19.Wm. Walter Phelps to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. May 22.E.L.P. to Sam Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 7. May 24.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 8. May 26. The Lands of Tahuahlo from The Two Republics by Geo. W. Clarke., Clip.
  - 9. May 30.to Josephine Fenton., A.L.S. E.L.P.
  - 10. May 30.to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S. E.L.P.
  - 11. May 30.from Le Trait d'Union., Clip. in Sp.
  - 12. May 31.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. June 1.J.A. Dacus to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. June 6.[Parke] Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. June 9.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 16. June 29.Thomas A. Scott to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. July 3.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. July 13.[Strickland d'Kurass] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. July 14.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. July 15.Hyde Clarke to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 21. July 15.James M. Swank to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. July 16.John L. Geiger to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. July 20.Wm. Walter Phelps to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 24. Aug. 1.D.S. Richardson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. Aug. 2.Wm. Henry Hurlbert to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 26. Aug. 5.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada. Financial situation., A.L.S.
  - 27. Aug. 10.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. Aug. 10.E.L.P. to Thomas Allen., A.L.S.
  - 29. Aug. 11.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 30. & 31. Aug. 14.E.L.P. to Hamilton Fish., A.L.S. & df. (copies).
  - 32. Aug. 18.E.L.P. to Thomas A. Scott., A.L.S.
  - 33. Aug. 30.E.L.P. to Jas. H. Morley., A.L.S. (copy).
- CORRESPONDENCE 1875, September - December (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1. Sep. 6.E.L.P. to Hamilton Fish., A.L.S.
  - 2. Sep. 10.Hamilton Fish to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. Sep. 10.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 4. Sep. 22.Mr. & Mrs. H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., Ptd. invitation.
  - 5. Oct. 1.Ptd. letter from I.N. Marks to E.L.P.
  - 6. Oct. 11.D.S. Richardson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 7. Oct. 18.Ptd. announcement, Congregational Club (Boston) with by A.H. [Plumb]., A.N.S.
  - 8. Oct.Form letter to be used in raising funds for Mexican International Railroad.
  - 9. Nov. 3.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 10. Nov. 6.E.L.P. to Walton W. Evans., A.L.S.
  - 11. & 12. Nov. 10.T.W. Pierce to E.L.P., L. (copy) & Sp. trans.
  - 13. Nov. 11.E.L.P. to Eljah Ward., A.L.S.
  - 14. Nov. 11.W. Milner Roberts to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. & 16. Nov. 11.T.W. Samuel Sloan to E.L.P., L. (copy) & Sp. transl.
  - 17. Nov. 12.E.P. Barhyde to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. & 19. Nov. 13.Thomas Allen to E.L.P., L. (copy) & Sp. transl.
  - 20. Nov. 13.E.L.P. to Wm. Walter Phelps., A.L.S.
  - 21. Nov. 13.[Manuel Ma de Zamacona] to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 22. - 24. Nov. 14.William Bond to E.L.P., L-P.S., copy & Sp. transl.
  - 25. Nov. 18.E.L.P. to Thomas Allen., A.L.S.
  - 26. Nov. 19.John W. Foster to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 27. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to J. Sanford Barnes., A.L.S.
  - 28. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 29. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 30. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 31. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to Moses Taylor., A.L.S.
  - 32. Nov. 19.Document appointing E.L.P. as Special Commissioner for the Republic of Mexico at the Southern States Agricultural & Industrial Exposition, with cvr.
  - 33. Nov. 19.Samuel Mullen to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 34. Nov. 20.E.L.P. to Jas. H. Morley., A.L.S.
  - 35. Nov. 20.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 36. Nov. 20.E.L.P. to Samuel Mullen., A.L.S.
  - 37. Nov. 27.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 38. Nov. 29.E.L.P. to Wm. Walter Phelps., A.L.S.
  - 39. & 40. Dec. 1.E.L.P. to Minister of Public Works., A.L.S. & Sp. transl.
  - 41. Dec. 3.Samuel Sloan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 42. Dec. 4.D. in Sp. (copy) & Eng. transl. Blas Balcarcel.
  - 43. Dec. 8.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 44. Dec. 17.Estanislao Cañedo to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 45. Dec. 21.D.S. Richardson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 46. Dec. 21.Julius A. Skilton to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 47. Dec. 29.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S. & copy.
  - 48. [1875?].Mary Audenreid to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 49. [1875?].W.H. Hurlbert to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 50. 1875.Population statistics.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1876, January - April (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1. Jan. 4.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 12.[R.S. Hayes] to E.L.P., T.N.
  - 3. Jan. 15.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 20.Holograph memo by E.L.P. from London Times. Foreign [debts] of Mexico with cvr.
  - 5. Jan. 29.E.L.P. to Robt, McLane., A.L.S.
  - 6. Jan. 29.E.T. Yardley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. Jan. 31.Chas. Babbidge to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 4.E.L.P. to Thos. W. Pearsall., A.L.S.
  - 9. Feb. 7.Robt. L. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Feb. 7.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall. Mexican RR business, relations toward Cuba., A.L.S.
  - 11. Feb. 7.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada. Telegraph line construction, border questions; Gen. Ord., A.L.S.
  - 12. Feb. 16.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Mexican revolutionary troubles - Oaxaca, Donata Guerra., A.L.S.
  - 13. Feb. 21.George E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. Feb. 21.Robt. M. McLane to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Feb. 24.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Mexican situation grave., A.L.S.
  - 16. Feb. 29.E.L.P. to N.P. Banks., A.L.S.
  - 17. Feb. 29.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 18. Mar. 1.E.L.P. to Abram S. Hewitt., A.L.S.
  - 19. Mar. 3.Wm. Hunter to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. Mar. 4.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes. Centennial exposition - mineral exhibit., A.L.S.
  - 21. Mar. 7.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. Mar. 14.Wm. P. Blake to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 23. Mar. 14.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Mexican situation., A.L.S.
  - 24. Mar. 16.W. Milnor Roberts to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. - 27. Mar. (n.d.)Internat'l & Gt. Northern RR Cos.; St. Louis, Iron Mt. & Southern RR Cos. to E.L.P. Time extension on Mexican RR concession., 3 form letters. (2)
  - 28. Apr. 2.E.L.P. to Ignacio Mariscal., A.L.S.
  - 29. Apr. 2.E.L.P. to Elijah Ward., A.L.S.
  - 30. Apr. 4.[W.H. Delano?] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. Apr. 4.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L.P. Diaz supported by Texans?., A.L.S.
  - 32. Apr. 4.E.L.P. to Hamilton Fish. U.S. - Mexican relations from 1858., A.L.S.
  - 33. & 34. Apr. 8.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel., 2 A.L.S.
  - 35. Apr. 8.E.L.P. to Estanislao Canedo, A.L.S.
  - 36. Apr. 8.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 37. Apr. 8.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 38. Apr. 18.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 39. Apr. 22.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 40. Apr. 25.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 41. Apr. 26.E.L.P. to T.W. Pierce., A.L.S.
  - 42. Apr. 27.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 43. Apr. 28.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1876, May - July (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1. May 2.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 2. May 2.E.L.P. to Estanislao Cañedo, A.L.S.
  - 3. May 2.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 4. May 2.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 5. May 3.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. May 5.E.L.P. to W.T. Sherman., A.L.S.
  - 7. May 12.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. May 13.Blas Balcarcel to E.L.P., L.S. in Sp.
  - 9. May 13.Wm. Cross Buchanan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. May 14.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. May 17.Edward Young to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 12. May 19.E.L.P. to Chas. Sligo de Pothonier., A.L.S.
  - 13. May 20.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 14. May 20.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 15. May 23.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 16. May 24.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. May 29.George E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 18. May 29.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. June 2.Blas Balcarcel to E.L.P., L.S. in Sp.
  - 20. June 3.N.A. Cowdrey to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. June 3.C. Sligo de Pothonier, to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. June 8.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P. Cuban affairs., A.L.S.
  - 23. June 13.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 24. June 13.C. Sligo de Pothonier to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. June 27.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. June 29.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 27. July 3.E.L.P. to Estanislao Cañeda., A.L.S.
  - 28. July 3.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 29. July 9.L. extract. Unknown to unknown. Published in St. Louis Republican, includes portions of reports & statistics.
  - 30. July 10.E.L.P. to Gastave Schleicher., A.L.S.
  - 31. July 11.E.L.P. to H.M. Hoxie., A.L.S.
  - 32. July 13.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 33. July 13.E.L.P. to Frederick Watts., A.L.S.
  - 34. July 14.E.L.P. to George E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 35. July 14.E.L.P. to Chas. Sligo de Pothonier., A.L.S.
  - 36. July 15.Blas Balcarcel to E.L.P., 2 A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 37. July 18.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 38. July 19.Samuel Sloan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 39. July 21.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 40. July 21.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
  - 41. July 24.H.M. Hoxie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 42. & 43. July 24.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel, 2 A.L.S.
  - 44. July 25.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 45. July 25.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 46. July 25.E.L.P. to John L. Geiger., A.L.S.
  - 47. July 25.E.L.P. to E.O.C. Ord., A.L.S.
  - 48. July 26.John W. Foster to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 49. July 26.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 50. July 27.Frank S. Bond to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 51. - 53. July 27.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., 3 A.L.S.
  - 54. July 27.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 55. July 28.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 56. July 29.Charles D. Posten to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 57. July 31.E.L.P. to Samuel Sloan., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1876, August (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1. Aug. 1.E.L.P. to Moses Taylor., A.L.S.
  - 2. Aug. 4.E.L.P. to Barring Brothers & Co., A.L.S.
  - 3. Aug. 4.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 4. Aug. 6.John W. Foster to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 5. Aug. 7.with partial transl. S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., L.S. in Sp.
  - 6. Aug. 10.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 7. Aug. 10.E.L.P. to D.C. Jenkins., A.L.S.
  - 8. Aug. 10.E.L.P. to Whitelaw Reid., A.L.S.
  - 9. Aug. 11.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Aug. 12.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Aug. 12.Chas. Sligo de Pothonier to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. Aug. 15.E.L.P. to Blas Balcarcel., A.L.S.
  - 13. Aug. 18.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 14. Aug. 18.Benj. Perley Poore to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Aug. 19.E.L.P. to W.P. Blake., A.L.S.
  - 16. Aug. 19.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 17. Aug. 19.E.L.P. to H.M. Hoxie., A.L.S.
  - 18. Aug. 22.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 19. Aug. 24.E.L.P. to A.K. MacMillan., A.L.S.
  - 20. Aug. 25.Wm. Newbold to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. Aug. 25.E.L.P. to A.K. MacMillan., A.L.S.
  - 22. Aug. 26.Blas Balcarcel to E.L.P., L.S. in Sp.
  - 23. Aug. 27.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 24. Aug. 27.Wm. Walter Phelps to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. & 26. Aug. 28.John W. Foster to E.L.P., 2 A.L.S.
  - 27. Aug. 28.W. Milner Roberts to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. Aug. 30.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 29. Aug. 31.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1876, September - October (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1. Sep. 2.E.L.P. to Thomas Allen., A.L.S.
  - 2. Sep. 2.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 3. Sep. 2.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes., A.L.S.
  - 4. Sep. 4.Thomas Allen to E.L.P. Steamers, RR., A.L.S.
  - 5. Sep. 5.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada, A.L.S.
  - 6. Sep. 5.E.L.P. to Edward Young., A.L.S.
  - 7. Sep. 5.W. Milnor Roberts to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Sep. 8.E.L.P. to C. Sligo de Pothonier., A.L.S.
  - 9. Sep. 10.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Sep. 12.William Bond to E.L.P., L.S. & Sp. transl.
  - 11. Sep. 12.T.W. Pierce to E.L.P., L.S. & Sp. transl.
  - 12. Sep. 13.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. Sep. 14.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 14. Sep. 14.E.L.P. to H.C. Marquand., A.L.S.
  - 15. Sep. 14.Samuel Sloan to E.L.P., L.S. & Sp. transl.
  - 16. Sep. 15.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., L.S. & Sp. transl.
  - 17. Sep. 16.E.L.P. to C. Sligo de Pothonier to E.L.P. Narrow gauge RRs., A.L.S.
  - 18. Sep. 19.C.P. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. Sep. 20.W. Newbold to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. Sep. 26.E.L.P. to Wm. W. Phelps., A.L.S.
  - 21. Sep. 26.E.L.P. to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. Sep. 26.E.L.P. to C. Sligo de Pothonier., A.L.S.
  - 23. Sep. 26.E.L.P. to D.S. Richardson., A.L.S.
  - 24. Oct. 6.[C. Lamburg?] to [E.L.P.?]., A.L.S.
  - 25. Oct. 6.E.L.P. to F. Alexander & Son., A.L.S.
  - 26. Oct. 11.Antonino [Faglet] to E.L.P., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 27. Oct. 11.Luis Ramiro to E.L.P., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 28. Oct. 12.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. Oct. 14.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 30. Oct. 14.E.L.P. to T.W. Pierce., A.L.S.
  - 31. Oct. 15.J.M. Mata to E.L.P., A.N. in Sp.
  - 32. Oct. 16.W. Milner Roberts to E.L.P. Channel at mouth of Mississippi., A.L.S.
  - 33. Oct. 21.A. [Pornel] to E.L.P., A.N.S. in Sp.
  - 34. Oct. 24.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P. Cuban situation., A.L.S.
  - 35. Oct. 29.E.L.P. to John W. Foster. Failure of Iglesias coup d'etat., A.L.S.
  - 36. Oct. 29.E.L.P. to Wm. Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 37. Oct. 29.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1876, November - December (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1. Nov. 15.E.L.P. to H.B. Andrews., A.L.S.
  - 2. Nov. 20.Manuel Romero Rubio to unknown., L. (copy) in Sp.
  - 3. Nov. 22.Wm. Hunter to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. Nov. 28.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. Dec. [?].[Juan des Mata River a?] to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 6. Dec. 7.Mr. & Mrs. Wm. E. Sanford to E.L.P., Ptd. invitation.
  - 7. Dec. 8.Estanislao Cañedo to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Dec. 8.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 9. Dec. 12.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 10. Dec. 23.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 11. Dec. 26.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. Dec. 26.E.L.P. to Juan N. Navarro., A.L.S.
  - 13. Dec. 26.E.L.P. to J.S. [Urtmore]., A.L.S.
  - 14. [1876].F. Lopez to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp. & cvr.
  - 15. [1876].H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. [1876].Ptd. form to Brown Brothers & Co.
  - 17. [1876].[E.L.P.] to John W. Foster. New England interest in foreign markets., A.D.
  - 18. [1876].List of books & pamphlets.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1877, January - March (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 1. Jan. 5.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall. Overthrow of gov't. in Mexico. Iglesias & Mejia fail, Diaz successful. Mejia & Santacilia banished., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 5.Edw. Thornton to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 8.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 8.E.L.P. to John L. Geiger., A.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 10.E.L.P. to Sir Edw. Thornton., A.L.S.
  - 6. Jan. 11.Edw. Thornton to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 7. [Jan. 12 rcvd.]Wm. H. Hurlbert to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Jan. 12.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 9. Jan. 15.E.L.P. to Chas. P. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 10. Jan. 16.Chas. P. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Jan. 19.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. Jan. 24.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. Jan. 27.E.L.P. to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. Jan. 31.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 15. Jan.Navarro y Manez to unknown., L.S. in Sp. (ptd.)
  - 16. Feb. 3.E.L.P. to Col. Audenreid., A.L.S.
  - 17. Feb. 5.John L. Geiger to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. Feb. 7.J.W. ? xel to E.L.P., A.L.S.